sussex.ac.uk 2017-11-17

# Privacy statement : The website : About us : University of Sussex

This Privacy Policy sets out the data processing practices carried out through the use of the Internet and any other electronic communications networks by the University of Sussex.

## Information collected

We collect information from visitors to this website through the use of online forms. We collect your details when you email us with an enquiry. We also collect information about the transactions you undertake through this site including details of payment cards used.

In addition to the above, we collect information automatically about your visit to our website. Please see the section on ‘Cookies’ for more details.  

If you have any requests concerning your personal information please contact the Information Officer at [dpo@sussex.ac.uk.](mailto:%20dpo@sussex.ac.uk)

### Use of personal information

We may process personal information collected via this website or other electronic communications networks used by the University, for the following purposes.

#### Advertising, Marketing, Public Relations, General Advice Services:

    * The identification of recipients for University services and administration of promotional campaigns
    * The advertising and promotion of the University and its services including by direct marketing means
    * The advertisement and provision of general advice to members of the public about University services
    * The advertisement and promotion of the University through third party products and services e.g. financial sponsorship
    * Fundraising for the University and other organisations (excluding fundraising through alumni).

#### Accounts and records:

      * The administration of supplier records relating to goods, orders, services
      * Accounts provided to the University

#### Education:

      * Administration of education and training such as registration
      * Calculation and publication of exam results, provision of references
      * Provision of education and training such as the planning and control of curricula and exams, and commissioning, validating and producing educational materials
      * Administration of applications e.g. receipt and processing of UCAS forms, compilation of statistics, assessments including preliminary and confirmed offers, liaison with UCAS
      * Preparation of DFEE returns
      * Administration of student awards and fees
      * Administration of the discipline scheme
      * Administration of the academic appeals scheme
      * Administration of visiting and exchange students and students on the year abroad

#### Student Support Services:

      * Administration and management of University and privately owned property including accommodation services
      * Administration of grants and loans e.g. student loans and access loans
      * Administration and provision of health care services
      * Administration and provision of library services including membership records, loan/hire records, information and databank administration
      * Ticket issue/reservation services
      * Administration and provision of a student card
      * Administration and provision of welfare and pastoral services
      * Careers guidance
      * Provision of creche facilities
      * Administration and provision of computing facilities
      * Administration and provision of student union services
    * Other commercial or information services such as the University magazines

#### Alumni relations:

    * The promotion of the relationship between the University and its alumni
    * University-related fundraising initiatives involving alumni
    * Advertising and promotion of alumni events and reunions
    * Distribution of University mailings e.g. alumni magazines, newsletters, annual reports, and message forwarding (without disclosure of data)
    * The promotion of benefits and services available to alumni from third parties
    * Eliciting non-financial support such as careers advice to students and help with student recruitment
  * Advertising, Marketing & Public Relations For Others

## Data Capture Information

We will send you information according to the preferences you submitted via our online form. If you would like to change these preferences at any point, please:

  * Use the link on the bottom of the last email you received from us if you are a prospective or existing student
  * Email [alumni@sussex.ac.uk](mailto:alumni@sussex.ac.uk) if you are a former student

Alternatively you can call us on 01273 877456 (prospective / existing students) or 01273 678258 (former students). Alternatively you can also write to us at Marketing, University of Sussex, Sussex House, Brighton, BN1 9RH.

## Marketing

Please note that your information may be used to send you details of those products or services that we offer that we have identified as likely to be of interest to you. This will be in accordance with the preferences that you indicated when you completed the application form or the online form.

Please contact us using the link on the bottom of the last email you received from us, or write to Marketing, University of Sussex, Sussex House, Brighton, BN1 9RH, if at any point you would like to:

  * opt-out of receiving communications from us
  * change the channels (such as email or post) that we use to contact you 
  * ask us at any point not to share your information with third parties for marketing purposes.

## Data Protection and disclosures

Any personal data captured by the University is used and held in accordance with the requirements of the Data Protection Act 1998.

We will only disclose data when obliged to disclose personal data by law or we have your consent, and to the following:

  * Other companies within our group of companies
  * University of Sussex Student Union
  * Business partners
  * Suppliers we engage to process data on our behalf or marketing companies employed by the University (where we have a non-disclosure agreement)
  * Funding councils and other funding bodies
  * Higher Education Statistics Agency
  * Legal representatives

## Subject access requests

You have the right to see what personal data we hold about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information we hold about you, please write to the Information Officer at Planning, Governance and Compliance, University of Sussex, Sussex House, Brighton, BN1 9RH or email [dpo@sussex.ac.uk](mailto:dpo@sussex.ac.uk). Please note that we reserve the right to charge a fee of up to £10 for any such request.

## Other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites that are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. If you access other sites using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect information from you that will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours.

## Internet-based transfers

Given that the Internet is a global environment, using it to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. This means, for instance, that data you pass to us may be processed outside the European Economic Area, although the data will always be held securely and in line with the requirements of UK data protection legislation. By communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge and agree to our processing of personal data in this way.

## Use of cookies

A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enables the server to collect information from the browser. You can find out more about cookies on [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

The University of Sussex makes limited use of cookies while you are browsing the website. We generally only use session-based cookies, which are deleted when you close your browser. Our cookies are anonymous, containing no information that can identify you personally.

We do use some third-party widgets on the site, such as Google Analytics, Twitter, YouTube, and Flickr. These widgets may set cookies. However, the cookie information from each of these sites is usually anonymous, unless you are logged in to those third-party systems while you are on our site.

By using this website, you consent to the storing of the cookies listed below. We may also use some cookies that are not listed – these will contain no personal information about you. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, although this means you might not be able to use the full functionality of our website.

Information about how cookies can be controlled within the various browsers:

You can find more information about cookies with the following resources:

We want you to be confident about your privacy when using our website, so if you have any questions that aren’t answered here, please contact [webteam@sussex.ac.uk](mailto:webteam@sussex.ac.uk).

### What cookies do we use?

#### University of Sussex

There may be a number of cookies set via our website, depending on what part of our system you log in to. All of the following are considered essential cookies for the operation of the website and services you log in to (such as the WCM and Study Direct):

Name| Life| Purpose  
---|---|---  
PHPSESSID | session | Used by PHP to store the session ID (e.g. for Sussex Direct login)  
UUcm | session | Facilitate logging in to and using the WCM  
BroadcastUS | session | Facilitate logging in to and using Broadcast  
SPLASH | session | Facilitate logging in to and using SPLASH  
PastExamPaperSearchSID | session | Provides access to the Past Exam Papers search facility  
StudentdirectorySID | session | Provides access to the Student Directory lookup  
MOODLEID_studydirect | session | To facilitate logging in to and using Study Direct  
MoodleSessionTeststudydirect | session | To facilitate logging in to and using Study Direct  
MoodleSessionstudydirect | session | To facilitate logging in to and using Study Direct  
  
#### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc.

Google Analytics uses cookies to help analyse how the website is used. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for us and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf.

Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.

Name| Life| Purpose  
---|---|---  
__utmz | 

182 days

| 

Stores where a visitor came from (search engine, search keyword, link)  
  
__utma | 

730 days

| 

Stores each user's amount of visits, and the time of the first visit, the previous visit, and the current visit (presumably partly for double checking of this information).  
  
__utmb | 

less than a day

| 

Used to check approximately how long you stay on a site: when a visit starts, and approximately ends  
  
__utmc | 

session based

| 

Same as __utmb  
  
__utmv | 

730 days

| 

Used for user-custom variables in Analytics  
  
This website uses Google Analytics Demographics and Interest reporting. Visitors can opt-out by using the [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). Visitors can also opt out using the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

Further information about Google products and cookies can be found at [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html) and [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics)

#### DoubleClick

Parts of this website use DoubleClick cookies. DoubleClick uses cookies to improve advertising. Some common applications are to target advertising based on what is relevant to a user, to improve reporting on campaign performance and to avoid showing ads the user has already seen. [More information on DoubleClick](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090?hl=en-GB)

#### Twitter

Parts of this website use Twitter feeds, a micro-blogging platform by Twitter, Inc. Twitter widgets may add third-party cookies - those not set directly by our site - to help analyis usage and remember your session if you are also logged in to the Twitter service. To that end, Twitter widgets may set all of the cookies that Google Analytics set (above) and also:

Name| Life| Purpose  
---|---|---  
_twitter_sess | session | Remember your logged in Twitter session  
  
Further information can be found at [Twitter Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy)

#### YouTube

Parts of this website contain embedded videos from YouTube. Where possible, we have set this to use YouTube's 'nocookie' domain so that it will not store any cookies. However, due to the different editors for the various sections of the overall University of Sussex website it i not always possible to guarantee that cookies will not be set. Further information can be found at [YouTube Privacy Policy](https://www.youtube.com/static?template=privacy_guidelines)

#### Vimeo

Parts of this website contain embedded videos from Vimeo. Where possible, we have set this to use YouTube's 'nocookie' domain so that it will not store any cookies. Further information can be found at [Vimeo's list of cookies](https://vimeo.com/cookie_list) and [Vimeo's privacy policy](https://vimeo.com/privacy)

#### Flickr

The code provided by Flickr to include various images and galleries may by default set cookies. Further information can be found at [Flickr Privacy Policy](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/flickr/details.html)

#### AppNexus

Parts of this website use AppNexus cookies. AppNexus uses unique cookies to identify web browsers and to store data for advertising purposes, including interest-based advertising. AppNexus is designed to use only non-Personal Identifiable Information (PII), and AppNexus has contractual provisions that prohibit clients of the Platform from associating Platform cookies with PII. AppNexus uses cookies to associate non-PII with browsers and devices, so that clients can then use the information to select ads for delivery by the Platform.

Further information can be found on the [Appnexus website](http://appnexus.com/cookies).

#### Facebook

Parts of this website use Facebook cookies and pixels. Pixels are small blocks of code on webpages that do things like allow another server to measure viewing of a webpage and often are used in connection with cookies. Cookies and pixels are used to understand and deliver ads and make them more relevant to you. Further information can be found on the [Facebook website](https://en-gb.facebook.com/about/privacy).

## Amendments

Please note that this privacy policy is subject to change from time to time. It was last updated in September 2015.
